<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Currency Converter</string>
    <string name="about">This app is made by Saranya Gopakumar, Shilpa S Chinchole, Cherukuru Mounika, Daisia Davis E, Shijith K S. This app took over a month to
        make, considering the fact it was made during lockdown, with low quality of internet and other issues. </string>
    <string name="report"><![CDATA[<p>A currency converter is software code that is designed to convert one currency into another in order to check its corresponding value.
        The code is generally a part of a web site or it forms a mobile app and it is based on current market or bank exchange rates.</p>
        <p>In order to convert one currency
        into another, a user enters an amount of money (e.g. "1000")and chooses the currency he/she wishes to check the monetary value of (e.g. "United StatesDollar").
        After that, the user selects one, or sometimes several other currencies, he/she would like to see the result in. The application software then calculates and
        displays the corresponding amount of money.</p>
        <p>Currency converters aim to maintain real-time information on current market or bank exchange rates, so that the
        calculated result changes whenever the value of either of the component currencies does. They do so by connecting to a database of current
        currency exchange rates.</p>

        Currency converters usually display a value that is not biased towards buying or selling. This is useful when:
        <ul>
            <li>Estimating the value of goods or services</li><br>
            <li>Basic accounting and invoicing</li><br>
            <li>Preparing financial plans and reports</li><br>
            <li>The currency conversion software calculates the rates as decimal point numbers with typically 4 decimals after the comma. Some may calculate the
                conversion rates with more decimals internally but only 4 are displayed. This is related to precision, software internalization and how the
                international markets work, where most conversions have 4decimal places, although some currency pairs also have 5.
                Most currency converters use upto 4.</li>
        </ul>

        <h2>Aim</h2>
        <p>The main aim of this application is to utilize JAVA programming language for the implementation of real time currency conversion.
            The application is to be developed to represent dynamic functionalities as that of online currency converters. The application can perform for
            simultaneous currency conversion by utilizing online information source. This application also provides a Graphical User Interface for currency
            conversion and commandline interface for data stream</p>
        <h3>BENEFITS OF CURRENCY CONVERTER APP</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>The Currency converter app is specifically programmed to do the entire task of monetary calculations for the user and because these apps are
                synchronized with the internet,they get the updated rate of exchange at all times, leaving no room for discrepancies. No currency exchange or
                transaction is ever possible without a good currency converter, at least to the best of our knowledge.</li><br>
            <li>Currency converter Apps come in handy, are simple, are accurate and are fast to be employed in any situation as the user just has it either
                directly on his smart phone or computer system, providing him/her quick and real time access to doing business within and outside the shores of
                the country without fear of making human error that is a characteristic of most these transactions.</li><br>
            <li>Currency converter Apps are mostly free and come ad free too. They are ingrained with the unique feature that links all of them to a currency page
                online. Which proof reads them with the needed database that allows you discover in-depth the knowledge of individual currencies. Most of these
                converter Apps follows every currency being traded and offers a multiple-currency display to help you keep track of relative trends simultaneously
                and keeping you updated as well.</li><br>
            <li>Currency converter Apps are able to handle a large number of popular currencies, it also has in built in it, several options that would make it
                appeal to a large number of business people. It has the ability to be operated in offline mode – to save on the bandwidth and data time. In addition,
                it can track changes in the international markets and display it as a graph, helping to predict future trends and giving analytics. Paired with a
                constant update of currency news, this if you will agree with me is a major benefit of Currency Converters that exist as apps.</li><br>
            <li>Currency converter Apps can be depended on for accurate and fast information. It is dependable to provide information on real time. These apps
                have and easy to navigate,pleasing and easy to use interface, presents the latest data on world currencies and precious metals. Users can even have
                all such data tracked in real-time.</li>
        </ul>



    ]]></string>
</resources>